

IMAN NADEEM

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT ME AT



iman.nadeem.825@gmail.com



262-613-9136



github.com/imannadeem825



in linkedin.com/in/imannadeem



imannadeem825.github.io

SKILLS

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | React | C# .Net | JSON server | Git

ABOUT ME

Before beginning my journey as a software developer, I've worked in customer service positions and in the medical field. I also have been a musician for most of my life. I come from a family of physicians and have come to appreciate and understand what it means to serve people, and make a huge impact on their lives, not just "help" them. People come first in my life, and I believe that value has led me to develop strong interpersonal and communication skills. I naturally gravitate towards opportunities that can challenge me intellectually, allow me to be creative, and give me a chance to invest in any of my passions. After hearing from friends that software development could fulfill all those desires, I knew I had to give it a shot. I'm so happy I took a step towards a career that not only keeps me on my toes every day, but also lets me be part of a team that can only accomplish its goals when its members are truly working together.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack Software Developer

November 2020 - May 2021

- Intensive, full-time software development program learning full-stack technologies by creating applications in group and individual settings
 - Built single page applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React
 - Hands-on, fast-paced simulated work environment, for both individual assignments and team projects
 - SQL Server database, writing database scripts, querying databases
 - Experience with remote collaboration
 - Git and GitHub for version control

Personal Projects

Memo to Demo, Front-End Capstone

- Memo to Demo is an application for songwriter-producers to organize their original content into task lists. It allows a user to enter information about songs that are in progress, and have all songs display in a list. Then, a user can add a demo to be completed that corresponds with a song in the songs list. Tracks to be completed can be added to each demo. Users can update and delete any information in the application. Collaborated with other designers
 - Single page, full CRUD React application utilizing React hooks to manage state
 - JSON-server used as local database
 - Styling with CSS3

Back-End Capstone

- description
 - more description

Group Projects

Nutshell

- A single page social media app with messaging, events, news and a tasks list
 - Individually responsible for tasks list, with delete capability
 - Team collaborated on entity relationship diagram, wireframe and dependency graph
 - Fetched data from local JSON-Server and used browser local and session storage

Tahloid

- A full CRUD ASP.NET application created in two stages, MVC and fullstack, with different groups respectively
- Multi-page blogging platform with posts, comments, categories, tags, user authentication
- SQL Server as database engine
- MVC
 - individually responsible for comments, with CRUD capability
 - Razor templating syntax for view models
- Full-stack
 - Firebase user authentication
 - individually responsible for

WORK EXPERIENCE

SMILE DIRECT CLUB

Call Center Representative

December 2019 - April 2020

- Received inbound calls for customer care, conducted outbound calls for scheduling of appointments
 - Wrote scripts for live calls and voicemails
 - Worked with Five9, software for inbound and outbound calls

TIFF'S TREATS

Kitchen/Driver

April 2018 - September 2018

- Performed kitchen duties
- Trained new employees
- Drove for delivery orders

SODEXO

Caterer, Belmont University

September 2016 - September 2017

- Performed kitchen duties
- Served patrons
- Created displays
- Moved kitchen equipment
- Fast-paced environment

RESIN8

Sync Licensing/Artist Management intern

Summer 2016

- Entered metadata into system server
- Organized all in-house writer/artist information
- Managed excel documents
- Compiled research on music in TV and film spots as well as in-show music

MIDWEST PULMONARY CONSULTANTS, LLC

Office Assistant/Medical Scribe

Summer 2014, Summer 2015

- Worked one-on-one with patients, documented follow-up visits
- Scanned documents
- Organized and prepared medical charts for billing

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE AT BELMONT UNIVERSITY

PRISMATICS A CAPPELLA

Vice President

2015 - 2018

- Helped start group, establish constitution and officer roles
- Oversaw recruitment and retention of members
- Helped book rehearsal spaces and performances
- Addressed personal affairs within group
- Oversaw community outreach
- Arranged vocal charts

HOPE COUNCIL

Vice President of Administrative Relations

Fall 2016 - Spring 2017

- Acted as liaison between students and university administration
- Oversaw development of organization
- Helped organized World Culture Festival on campus
- Held and led meetings for general body
- Invited and coordinated with guest speakers
- Organized and held first leadership summit for all diversity organization student leaders

GENDER EQUALITY MOVEMENT

Vice President

2015 - 2017

- Helped start group, establish constitution and officer roles
- Led general body meetings
- Created topics for discussion
- Cultivated relationships with other diversity organizations on campus
- Oversaw member outreach and retention

EDUCATION

BELMONT UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Music | 2018

Major in Commercial Voice, Songwriting emphasis

- Cum Laude, Honors Scholar
- Omicron Delta Kappa Honor Society
- Senior Thesis "Unorthodox EP"

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Certificate, Software Development | 2021

Full Stack Software Development